A Guide to the Augusta County (Va.) Marriage Bonds, Volumes 1-13, 1785-1812
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Augusta County (Va.) Marriage Bonds, Volumes 1-13, 1785-1799
Library of Virginia
1146325-1146331, 1104242-1104245, 1104252-1104253
13 vols. (1947 p.) All volumes are negative photostatic copies.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Use microfilm copies, Augusta County, Reels 232-239.
Acquisition Information
These items came to the Library of Virginia in a transfer of court papers from Augusta County.
Historical Information
Augusta County was formed in 1738 from Orange County. Augusta's government was established in 1745.
In order to be married by license, the groom is required to go before the county clerk and give bond with security that there was no lawful reason to prevent the marriage. The license issued then by the clerk was given to the minister who performed the service. Written consent from a parent or guardian was needed for individuals younger than twenty-one years.
Scope and Content
Marriage bonds, Volumes 1-13, 1785-1812, of Augusta County Court record the names of the bride and groom and written consent forms from a parent or guardian.
Arrangement
Chronological.
Contents List
- Marriage Bonds, Volume 1, 1785-1786, 1146325
- Marriage Bonds, Volume 2, 1787-1789, 1146326
- Marriage Bonds, Volume 3, 1790-1793, 1146327
- Marriage Bonds, Volume 4, 1792-1793, 1146328
- Marriage Bonds, Volume 5, 1794-1795, 1146329
- Marriage Bonds, Volume 6, 1796-1797, 1146330
- Marriage Bonds, Volume 7, 1798-1799, 1146331
- Marriage Bonds, Volume 8, 1800-1801, 1104242
- Marriage Bonds, Volume 9, 1802-1803, 1104243
- Marriage Bonds, Volume 10, 1804-1805, 1104244
- Marriage Bonds, Volume 11, 1806-1807, 1104245
- Marriage Bonds, Volume 12, 1808-1809, 1104252
- Marriage Bonds, Volume 13, 1810-1812, 1104253